hawaiiantel.net 2013-12-26

# Hawaiian Telcom | Privacy Policy

## Our Commitment to Privacy

The privacy of your personally identifiable information is important to us. As part of our commitment to the privacy of the personally identifiable information that we collect from you online (“Personal Information”), we provide this notice explaining our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your Personal Information is collected and used at this site. This revised Privacy Policy is effective as of April 1, 2013.

The privacy practices set forth in this Privacy Policy are for the Hawaiian Telcom site located at www.hawaiiantel.com (the “Site”) only. All Other Hawaiian Telcom affiliate Web sites may have different practices and if you visit those sites you should review the privacy policies posted there.

This privacy policy applies to information collected through the Site and does not apply to information gathered through fax, phone, mail or other offline communications. Also, if you are an employee of Hawaiian Telcom or one of its affiliates, please note that other internal company policies related to employee use of company computer systems and networks apply to you.

## Consent

Please read this policy carefully. Your use of the Site constitutes your consent to the information collection, use, and disclosure practices described in this policy.

## Foreign Visitors

The Site is directed to persons located in the United States only, and is not intended for use by persons located in other countries.

## Active Information Collection

In general, when you visit the Site you remain anonymous, but on some pages, you may need to provide Personal Information to register, order products or services, contact us with questions or feedback, enter sweepstakes or online contests, or conduct other online transactions. Examples of the type of Personal Information that you may be asked to provide on the Site include: name, company, occupation, account number, mailing address, email address, phone number, fax number, credit/debit card/procurement card information, username, and passwords. We may request additional information to respond to a specific request from you or to complete a transaction that you request. For example, if you elect to order service or set up an account online, you may be asked to provide additional information (such as your Social Security number (SSN) and date of birth) that will allow us to research your credit and establish your account. We also enable you to submit personally identifiable information about other people. For example, if you elect to purchase a family wireless plan, you may be asked to provide the names, addresses and other information for family members who will participate in the plan.

## Passive Information Collection

The Web site may “passively” collect certain kinds of information during your visit, including but not limited to:

## Cookies

“Cookies” are small text files sent from a website to the hard drive of a user’s computer to store bits of information related to that user. Cookies can store a variety of information, including IP addresses, navigational data, server information, data transfer times, user preferences, and passwords needed to access the special areas on the Site. For example, we use cookies to identify who you are after you log in or register and to keep track of any purchases that you have made. We also use cookies to create a more personalized experience on the Site. For example, cookies can help us let you know what’s new on the Site since your last visit. You can configure your Internet browser to reject cookies. However, if you do so, you might not be able to access certain pages or use some functions on the Site. Other Passive Web Site Tracking. The Site also uses Internet Protocol (IP) addresses and log files to identify server problems, to improve site content, and compile aggregated statistics about usage of the Site. We also use Web beacons to help personalize your experience, similar to how we use cookies. Companies that help us place advertisements on our site use Web beacons to serve cookies and advertisements. We also use Web beacons to gather general, non-personally identifiable statistics on the number of users who visit the Site and the areas that they visit.

We reserve the right to introduce new passive tracking technologies and techniques related to the use of the Site. In general, we do not link your identity with information that we collect passively. However, in any situation where you log in with your username and password, any or all of the information that is passively collected about your activities on the Site may be linked with your identity, and therefore may become Personal Information about you.

## The Purposes for Which We Use and Disclose Personal Information

In general, we use Personal Information for billing purposes, to answer your service questions, to provide services, to anticipate and resolve problems with your service, or to create and inform you of products or services that you may find interesting. The following paragraphs provide some examples (but not an exhaustive list) of how we may use or disclose your Personal Information:

  * We may use Personal Information to communicate with you, for example, to answer the email and correspondence that you send us, to confirm your order for products or services and to provide you with notices related to the handling of your Personal Information. 
  * We may use Personal Information to make recommendations for additional products or special offers offered by us or our affiliates, and to provide you with updates on new products that we believe may be of interest to you. If you do not want to receive this information in the future, please contact us at 808-643-3456. 
  * We may share Personal Information with our consultants or service providers to help us serve you better. We also contract other companies and individuals (collectively “Suppliers”) to perform functions on our behalf, for example, processing credit card payments, handling shipping and returns, sending you communications, and providing you with customer service. Although our contracts with our Suppliers generally require them to keep your Personal Information confidential and only use your Personal Information to the extent necessary to perform their functions, we cannot promise that they will comply with these commitments or be responsible if they fail to do so. 
  * We may publish your name, address, and phone number in our directories unless you have requested a non-published or non-listed number. 
  * From time to time, we may share certain Personal Information with select, unaffiliated third parties to enable them to offer products or services that may be of interest to you. If you do not want us to share your Personal Information with such third parties in the future, please contact us at 808-643-3456 and we will take reasonable measures to avoid such sharing in the future. Please note that these third parties are independent from Hawaiian Telcom; therefore, you should contact them directly if you have any issues or concerns relating to their use of your information. 
  * We may disclose Personal Information in response to legal process or when we believe in good faith that the law requires it, for example, in response to a court order, subpoena or a law enforcement agency’s request. We also reserve the right to disclose Personal Information to protect the security of the Web site, to protect ourselves and our affiliated companies against liability, and/or in connection with any sale, assignment, or other transfer of all or a part of our business. 

## Customization and Aggregate data

We use non-identifying and aggregate information to better design our Site and gather information for product management and development. For example, we may tell our sales and marketing staff that X number of individuals visited a certain area on our Site, or that Y number of wireless handsets were ordered during a particular time period. This aggregate information may also be shared with our affiliates and independent dealers.

## Our Commitment to Data Security

We maintain reasonable physical, electronic, and organizational procedures to protect your Personal Information. When you place orders or access your account information, we usually offer the use of a server that interacts with your computer through the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) of your Internet browser. This encrypts Personal Information you input before it is sent to us and seeks to prevent anyone from reading it as the information travels from your computer to ours. Your browser should indicate when it is on an SSL protected page, and you should check for this indication if you are relying on SSL security to protect your Personal Information. If you are concerned about placing on order online, please feel free to call a customer service representative at **643-3456** and place your order via phone.

## Children's Privacy

The Hawaiian Telcom Web site is not designed to attract children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect information from or market online to children under the age of 13 at the Site.

## How You Can Access or Correct Your Information

If the Personal Information you have submitted through the Site is no longer accurate, current, or complete, and you wish to update it, please contact us at 808-643-3456. Alternatively, if you wish to change the information contained in your account profile, you can update that information at any time by using the [Update Account] feature within the "My Account" link. We will usually be glad to update your information, but we reserve the right to use Personal Information obtained previously to verify your identity or to administer the warranties associated with products or services you have purchased.

For questions related to updating or changing your account information, please call us at 808-643-3456 . If any errors in your Personal Information cannot be corrected by accessing “My Account”, please contact us using the contact information below. You may also contact us using the information below to ask us to remove your Personal Information from our records, electronic or otherwise. However, we will need to maintain certain Personal Information about your product purchases in our records for purposes such as warranty and product information, and may elect to keep additional information as may be required by law or necessary to protect our interests.

## Usernames and Passwords

It is your responsibility to safeguard any username or password that you have received in connection with the Site, and to notify us if you ever suspect that the security and confidentiality of such username or password has been compromised in any way. You are solely responsible for any use of the Site via your username and password.

## Collection of Personal Information by Third Parties

Sometimes we may offer promotions or specials that are sponsored by or co-sponsored with identified third parties. By virtue of their sponsorship, these third parties may obtain Personal Information that you submit to participate in the promotion or special. We have no control over the third-party sponsor’s use of this information. We will notify you at the time of requesting Personal Information if third-party sponsors will obtain such information, and obtain your prior expressed consent for such disclosures.

Additionally, we may enable access to third party services, such as Twitter or Facebook, through this site or through other services we offer, such as our Hawaiian Telcom TV Service. It is important to understand that Hawaiian Telcom assumes no responsibility for the security of those third party services, or how they collect, handle, and protect personal information you may provide to them. Customers should individually assess the privacy policies of those third party services prior to using them.

## Links to Other Sites

The Site may contain links to other Web sites. We are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by other sites. Please review the privacy policies applicable to any of these sites before disclosing your Personal Information on them.

## Changes to the Policy

Our privacy practices, like the online medium itself, are subject to change. We reserve the right to change this policy from time to time in our sole discretion. Please check this policy frequently and particularly before you submit additional Personal Information via the Site. In the event that we change a significant or material term in this Privacy Policy, we will notify affected visitors for a period of 30 days after the change by revising the link on the home page to read “Newly Revised Privacy Policy” that notifies visitors of the change.

## Governing Law; Agreement to Arbitrate

The laws of the State of Hawai'i shall govern any claims relating to the Site. By using the Site, you agree to arbitrate any dispute regarding this Privacy Policy, the Site or the use of your Personal Information in accordance with the Arbitration Rules, Procedures & Protocols of Dispute Prevention & Resolution, Inc. then in effect and with Hawai'i Revised Statutes §658A. The seat of the arbitration shall be Honolulu, Hawai'i. The parties further agree that the award of the arbitrator is binding upon the parties and that judgment on the award rendered by the arbitrator may be entered in any court with jurisdiction.

## How to Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about these privacy policies, please call us at 808-643-3456 or mail correspondence to Hawaiian Telcom, PO Box 2200, Honolulu, HI 96841.
